Guide to Peter P. Carr Papers RG.055
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Peter P. Carr Papers
0
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
RG.055
60 Linear Feet
Good
Content Description
Approximately 60 linear feet of Peter Carr's professional records, stored in boxes and file cabinets. These materials are mostly paper/text-based documents, including research papers, notes, and professional correspondence.
- Series I: American Options, 1977-2002; 60 Linear Feet
  - An Exact Analytic Formula for the Value of an American Put Option on a Non-Dividend-Paying Stock, 1994-08-11; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bibliography on American Options, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Derivatives - A Review; Aase; 1997, 1997-12-27; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - On Trading American Options; Ahn and Wilmott; OCIAM, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Optimal Stopping and Weak Convergence Methods for some Problems in Financial Economics; Ait-Sahlia, F., 1995-03; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Corrected Random Walk Approximations for Contingent Claims Problems; Ait-Sahlia, F; Stanford University, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Approximations for American Options; Ait-Sahlia and Lai, 1995-12-18; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Jumping in Line; Albanese, Jaimungal, and Rubisov; July 2000, 2000-07-28; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Pricing American Options in a Term Structure Economy; Amin, Kaushik; Cornell WP 1988, 1988-11-07; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Discrete-Time Valuation of American Optics with Stochastic Interest Rates; Amin, K.I. Bodurtha, J.N.; University of Michigan, 1993-07-1995; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Convergence of American Option Values from Discrete to Continuous Time Financial Models; Amin/Khanna 4/92, 1992-04; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - A Primal-Dual Simulation Algorithm for Pricing Multi-Dimensional American Options; Andersen and Broadie; July 2001, 2001-07; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Pricing American Options Using Monte Carlo Simulation; Averbukh, V.; Cornell U WP 97, 1997; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - A Method for Computing Double Band Policies for Switching Between Two Diffusions; Avram, F., 1996-03; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Analytic Representations and Approximations to American Option Pricing; Balakrishna, B.S.; UC Boulder WP, 1996-02; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Critical Stock Price Near Expiration; Barles, Burdeau, Romano, and Samsoen; Math Fin Apr 1995, 1995-04; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Convergence of Numerical Schemes for Parabolic Equations Arising in Finance Theory; Barles, G.; Newton Institute - Cambridge, 1995-04; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - American Path-Dependent Options; Barone-Adesi, Giovanni, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - The Free Boundary of American Puts; Barone-Adesi, Giovanni; 4/9/92, 1992-04-09; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Free Boundary Problems in the Valuation of Securities; Baron-Adesi; 11/89, 1989-11-14-1990-04-03; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - American Path-Dependent Options; G. Barone-Adesi and M. Chesney, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Approximations for the Values of American Options; Barone-Adesi/Elliot, 1989-10-27; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - The Valuation of American Options; Barone-Adesi and Elliot; Univ of Alberta 89, 1989-10-05-1990-08-08; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Efficient Analytic Approximation of American Option Values; Baron-Adesi/Whaley JF; 1987, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - On the Valuation of American Put Options on Dividend-Paying Stocks; Barone-Adesi and Whaley, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Numerical Valuation of High Dimensional Multivariate American Securities; Digital Equip. Corp; J. Barraquand and D. Martineau; April 1994, 1994-04; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - The Optimal Exercise Boundary of American Options; Basso, Nardon, and Pianca; Mar 2002, 2002-03-2002-04-19; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - An Analysis of the Effects of Continuous Dividends on the Exercise of American Options; Basso, Nardon, and Pianca; Venice WP 02, 2002-07-15; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Discrete and Continuous Time Approximations of the Optimal Exercise Boundary of American Options; Basso, Nardon, and Pianca, 2002-03-25; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Jumps and Stochastic Volatility: Exchange Rate Processes Implicit in Deutsche Mark Options; Bates, D.; RFS 96, 1996; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - A New Look at Optimal Stopping Problems Related, 1997; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Closed-Form Approximation of American Options; Bjerksund and Stensland; Scand. J. Mgmt 93, 1993; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - The Pricing of Options and Corporate Liabilities; Black/Scholes JPE, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - The Probability of Early Exercise: Foreign Currency Options and Foreign Currency Futures Options; Bodurtha, Courtadon; 1/93, 1993-01; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Simulation Estimators of Optimal Early Exercise; Bossaerts, Peter; 1989, 1989-02; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Pricing of the American Put Under Levy Processes; Beyarchenko, S; U Penn 02, 2002; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Options: A Monte Carlo Approach; Boyle, Phelim; JFE; 1977, 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - The Accelerated Binomial Option Pricing Model; Green, Richard, 1991-06; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - The Valuation of American Put Options; Brennan & Schwartz, 1977-05; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Finite Difference Methods and Jump Processes Arising in the Pricing of Contingent Claims: A Synthesis; Brennan/Schwartz, 1978; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Pricing American Options: Managing Risk with Early Exercise; Brill/Harriff, 1986; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - The Valuation of American Options on Multiple Assets; Broadie & Detemple, 1994; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - American Capped Call Options on Dividend-Paying Assets; Broadie, M. and Detemple, J., 1993-1995; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - American Options on Dividend-Paying Assets; Broadie & Detemple, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - American Option Valuation: New Bonds, Approximations, and a Comparison of Existing Methods; Broadie, M. and Detemple, J., 1995; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Nonparametric Estimation of American Options Exercise Boundaries and Call Prices; Broadie, Detemple, Ghysels, & Torres, 1996; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - American Options with Stochastic Dividends and Volatility: A Nonparametric Investigation; Broadie, Detemple, Ghysels & Torres, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Pricing American-Style Securities Using Simulation; Broadie & Glasserman, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - A Stochastic Mesh Method for Pricing High-Dimensional American Options; Broader & Glasserman, 1997-11; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Monte Carlo Methods for Pricing High-Dimensional American Options: An Overview; Broader & Glasserman, 1997-10; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - A Simple and Numerically Efficient Method for American Puts Using a Modified Geske-Johnson Approach; Bunch, D.S. & Johnson, H., 1992-06; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - The American Put Option and Its Critical Stock Price; Bunch & Johnson, 2000-10; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - On the Pricing of American Options When the Asset Follows a Mean-Reverting Process; Cadenillas, Elliott, & Leger, 2002-06-23; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Beyond the American Put; Carr, Elliott, Geman, & Madan, 1997-10; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Evaluation of American Option Prices in a Path Integral Framework Using Fourier-Hermite Series Expansions; Chiarella, El-Hassan & Kucera, 1997-09; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Premature Exercise and American Put Evaluation; Chesney & Lefoll, 1993-03; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - American Options: Theory and Numerical Analysis; Carverhill/Webber, 1988-07; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Richardson Extrapolation Techniques for Pricing American-style Options; Chang, Chung, & Stapleton, 2001-05-21; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Linear Complementarity and the American Put - A GAMS/PATH Implementation; Chan, S., 1998-09-03; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Analytical Upper Bounds for American Option Prices; Chen & Yeh, 1999-12; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Pricing American Currency Options: An Analytical Approach; Chesney, Marc, 1989; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Analytical Solutions to the Pricing of American Bond and Yield Options; Chesney, Elliott, Gibson, 1991-05; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - M. Chesney & R. Gibson, State Space Symmetry and Two Factor Option Pricing Models; IGBF IBFM #9402; 1993, 1993-10; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Clarke & Parrott; The Multigrid Solution of Two-factor American Put Options, 1996-08; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Efficient Monte Carlo Valuation and Hedging of Contingent Claims; Clewlow/Carverhill, 1992-03; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - The Wise, For Cure, on Exercise Depend; Cornwall/Price; Risk Magazine, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - A More Accurate Finite Difference Approximation for the Valuation of Options; Courtadon, G.; JFQA, 1982-12; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Options Markets; Cox & Rubinstein, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Accelerating American Option Pricing in Lattices; Curran, M., 1994-12-06; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - American Options and Transaction Fees; Davis, M.H.A. & Zariphopoulou, T., Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - On the Optimal Stopping Problems for One-Dimensional Diffusions with Random Discounting; Dayanik, Savas, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - On the Optimal Stopping Problem for One-Dimensional Diffusions; Dayanik, S. & Karatzas, I., Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - A Variational Approach for Pricing Options and Corporate Bonds; Decamps, J.P. & Rochet, J.C., 1993-07-19; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - The Ratio of American & European Put Options When Time to Maturity is Small; Delbaen, F., 2000-05; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Fast Numerical Valuation of American, Exotic and Complex Options; Applied Mathematical Finance; Dempster & Hutton, 1997-01; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Pricing American Stock Options by Linear Programming; Dempster & Hutton, 1999-08-24; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Pricing Exotic American Options Fitting the Volatility Smile; Dempster & Richards, 1999-03; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - The Valuation of American Options on the Minimum of Two Dividend-Paying Assets; Detemple, Feng, & Tian, 2001-02-05; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - The Valuation of American Options for a Class of Diffusion Processes; Detemple & Tian, 2002-02; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Some Mathematical Results in the Pricing of American Options; Euro. Journal of Applied Mathematics 4; Dewynne, J. N. & Howison, S.D., 1993; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - American Option Pricing under GARCH by a Markov Chain Approximation; Duan & Simonato, 1997-05; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - The Optimal Stopping Problem for a General American Put-Option; Karoui, N.E. & Karatzas, I., Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - American Options with Dividends Near Expiry; Evans, Kuske, & Keller, 2000-08-01; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - An Explicit Formula for American Puts; Firoozye, N., Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Analytic Approximation for the Valuation of American Put Options on Stocks with Known Dividends; Fischer, E.O., 1990-12; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - "Estimating Implied PDFs from American Options: A New Semi-Parametric Approach"; Flamouris, D.V. & Giamouridis, D.G., 2000-10-12; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Quadratic Convergence of a Penalty Method for Valuing American Options; Forsyth & Vetzal, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Valuation by Approximation: A Comparison of Alternative Option Valuation Techniques; Geske & Shastri, 1985-03; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - An Improved Analytic Approximation for American Option Pricing; Gandhi, Kooros, & Salkin, 1993-03-01; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - "A Monte Carlo Method for Pricing American Options"; Garcia, D., 1999-08-1999-09; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - A Monte Carlo Method for Pricing American Options, 2000-08-30; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Semper Tempus Fugit; Risk Magazine; Garman, M., Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - An Analytical Approach to the Valuation of American Path-Dependent Options; Gao, Huang, & Subrahmanyam, 1996-07-27; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Martingale Approach to Pricing Perpetual American Options on Two Stocks; Gerber & Shiu, 1996; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - The Valuation of Compound Options; JFE; Geske, R., 1979; 60 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - The American Put Option Valued Analytically; Geske and Johnson; JF Dec 84, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - The Early Exercise of American Puts; Geske, Robert and Shastri, Kuldeep; July 1981, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Estimating the Early Exercise Boundary and Pricing American Options; Goldenberg and Schmidt, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - On the Early Exercise Boundary of the American Put Option; Goodman and Ostrov; Aug 2000, 2000-08; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Path-Dependent Options: Extending the Monte Carlo Simulation Approach; Working Paper, 1993-11-30; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Simulation and the Early-Exercise Option Problem; Grant, Vora and Weeks; JFE, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Efficient Numerical Methods for Pricing American Options; Gukhal, Chandrasekhar; WP Nov 96, 1996-11; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The Analytical Valuation of American Options on Jump-Diffusion Processes; Gukhal, Reddy; Columbia WP 96, 1996; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - A General Approach to the Analytical Valuation of American Options; Gukhal, C.; Nov 2001, 2001-11-24; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Closed-Form Solutions for Perpetual American Put Options with Regime Switching; Guo and Zhang, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Exercise by Numbers; Guth, Michael 2/92, 1992-02; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "Multinomial Approximating Models for Options with k State Variables"; Kamrad/Ritchken, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Optimization Problems in the Theory of Continuous Trading; Karatzas, Ioannis, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - On the Pricing of American Options; Karatzas, Ioannis; Appl Math Optim 1988, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Valuing and Hedging American Put Options Using Neural Networks; Kelly, D.; CMU WP 94, 1994-12-15; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Valuation of American Options via Penalty Methods; Khaliq, Voss and Kazmi, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - The Analytic Valuation of American Options on Futures Contracts; Kim, In Joon; 1989, 1989-10; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - The Analytic Valuation of American Options; Kim, In Joon; WP S-90-15, 1989-03; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Analytic Approximation of the Optimal Exercise Boundaries for American Futures Options; Kim, J., Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - The Analytic Valuation of American Options; Kim, J.; Rev. Fin. Stud. 1990, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Predicting Early Exercise Premia in American Put Prices; Kim, Hongshik, 1994-09-06; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - A Simplified Approach to the Valuation of American Options and its Applications; Kim, Yu 2/93, 1993; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Optimal Exercise Boundary for an American Put Option; Kuske and Keller; Applied Math Fin 98, 2001; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - A Remark on American Securities; Kusuoka, S., Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Error Estimates for the Binomial Approximation of American Put Options; Lamberton, D.; Annals of Applied Prob 1998, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Convergence of the Critical Price in the Approximation of American Options; Lamberton, Damien 4/93, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Brownian Optimal Stopping and Random Walks; Lamberton, D., 1998 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Course on American Options; Laurence, Peter, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Bounds for the Price of an American Option on Several Assets: Index and Spread Options; Laurence, P., 2001-03-11 (Box 2, Folder 29)